At the moment when I have this phase of bending, and I have this phase of straightening
of my embryo,
I have my digestive tract at first quite low.
And if you now look at your palate, you see that it is pointed like this.
But before, in fact, it was rather low.
Because at the same time I have this phase of straightening inside,
I have this descent of my pterygoids downwards,
I have this rise here,
and I have a traction of my digestive tract that makes this, that rises.
So it is there and in this development, it creates a movement like this, there.
And in fact, what is pulling there?
It is the process of development for the tongue.
And at the same time, I will already add a part we call the thyroid.
The thyroid comes from the tongue.
In this section of the embryo, it represents here what we call the
endodermal part.
And we see the first pharyngeal arch here, corresponding to this one, the
second, third, and fourth pharyngeal arches.
And we see here, in the first pharyngeal arch, in the phase of development,
and this occurs at the same time as my straightening phase of the embryo,
we see the appearance on the surface here, in fact, what we call the layer of
the lateral tongue.
And we see here, between...
the part here, what we call the second branchial arch,
a tubercle we call the median tubercle,
and at the tip of this little tubercle here,
we see a little hole appear,
a small space we call the foramen cæcum.
You see the tongue developing here,
and in the straightening phase here of my embryo,
it is important to see that it is much larger,
the small space we call here,
well it is already there.
It is all this that has grown, creating this image of a hole
we call the foramen cæcum which will form the thyroid system.
So it is a global growth with a point, this time, that is a fixed point
that is set here.
In development, it is as if it were pulled.
So at first, it is there and it does this in relation to the development here.
That is where you have this pointed system.
That is why we say that the depth of...
the tongue represents
the depth of
telencephalization. I have this
straightening of the embryo, I have
the foramen cæcum that was here, that we see
and piqued there, piqued there,
piqued there, with all the formation.
Another section that shows us the same drawing.
I see laterally here
what we call Meckel's cartilage,
the tongue, and in the phase
of straightening, there is an error
in the arrows. The arrows should
be in the other direction.
To understand in the dynamics this area here, it is like a tearing between
there and my diaphragm.
I will have like a tearing of my muscles with the thyroid cartilage which
becomes a support point for all this.
I can press and do all this straightening here.
In relation to my tongue, that means stabilizing a tongue and stabilizing a vagus nerve,
is to give the balance point at the level of my thyroid cartilage and my hyoid bone.
Your tongue is your first postural activity.
The child straightens when he starts to get his first teeth,
because these are support points with his tongue.
We seek precision with our tongue.
It's like the wings of a bird, of an eagle; your diaphragm,
that can really open,
but it opens in all this phase of opening and stretching,
almost a tearing of the neck muscles,
with specific support points being made.
And so that's how everything can nicely extend.
And in fact, what we always seek is to have our support points.
then to breathe. Because every time you swallow your saliva, you close
your teeth and your tongue comes completely spread out, it tries to block all
the little holes. If there is a missing tooth, it seeks this contact on
the side. It
will move and therefore will deviate your axis. And I have discovered that in relation
to this axis
longitudinal which is the axis of my midline, thus an autocoidal, in relation to
all this
impact goes very far in the body
and among other things down to the pelvis
and sometimes you have pelvic deviations
that express an occlusal imbalance
in relation to what you can do on the lingual level in fact
and thus by modifying, raising, returning
the system can find its support points
so now why does everything go off track
there are memories in the teeth in fact
it is a zone of the strongest densification
So that means it keeps the so-called karmic charge, as they say.
That's what will remain of you.
So well understanding this dynamic, where we see that in this development phase,
you see laterally, we have what we call the palatine tonsils,
the parathyroid, the thymus, and the ultimobranchial body.
And inside here, we still have, from the foramen cæcum, the thyroid,
which actually corresponds to each arch.
we call the mandibular, thyroid, superior laryngeal, and inferior laryngeal branchial arches.
It's not just that it starts from the tongue, but it starts from all the space that is around here.
Inside, completely here, the endodermic tissue, hence digestive,
in the system, the cartilaginous system, and outside, the epiblastic system.
In 15 days, I have my notochord.
On the 27th day, I have the complete closure of my neural tube, 28th
day,
at the same time as the integration.
then after I have the straightening of my embryo that starts to be completely so
it is
after the first month so this whole complete phase develops between the second month
and the third month with a specific chronology knowing that at the end of the second
month you really have a complete form of an embryo, one could say it is already the
second month
of this phase with specific lines and specific synchronicities each arch
is composed from the outside
to the inside epiblastic ectodermic to the inside c
is all that is mesodermic with
the cartilaginous vascular part etc and inside it is all that
is endodermic
automatically and they influence each other because the ectoderm and the endoderm are dependent
on the mesoderm so it’s what we call the outer tissue is dependent on the inner tissue
it is the royal way that brings the information too
the nutritional information you understand a bit this dynamic how ultimately in
this
development phase, the tongue, the thyroid, the parathyroid develop
is only a
response to this complete phase of development with each time new support points and
new fulcrums that will develop it is important to learn to follow these fulcrums well, to understand them well
and to be able to orient you will see in practice it expresses itself
When we are in the right tissue resonance, the body recognizes it.
The great fulcrum is your navel.
The pelvis must be well cleared, well free.
That is very important.
And of course, the SSB.
That's why we often start by treating a pelvis.
Do I have a good dynamic?
I almost always start by looking at the pelvis.
As we saw, one of the first practices we did was the sacrum,
in relation to this spheno-basal symphysis, because they are...
So if I work on a sacrum or a pelvis, ultimately I am already working on a spheno-basal symphysis.
We do not work on a spheno-basal symphysis on the spheno-basal symphysis.
It's as if we were working the whole periphery towards my spheno-basal symphysis.